SOFTWARE ENGINEER TRAINEE

Summary

Over 3 years of professional IT experience in developing scalable, reliable and efficient enterprise applications using Java, Spring, Spring Boot, Web Services, JSP, jQuery, Angular 2, Servlets, Hibernate, JDBC, XML, Oracle, HTML, Java Script, DOM, Ajax, JSON, Bootstrap. *Having the strong emphasis on Business Requirements Analysis, Modeling (UML), Designing solutions and Implementation. *Having Good Experience in various MVC Frameworks- SPRING, Hibernate and Angular JS. *Experience in building Web Applications using Spring Modules like Spring MVC, AOP, DI, JMS, JDBC and ORM. *Experience in developing rich User Interface using Angular JS, JSP, JSON, JSTL, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, HTML, and CSS. *Experience in implementing Persistence Layer using JDBC, Spring DAO, and Hibernate. *Solid Experience with SQL, PL/SQL, and databases including Oracle, MySQL, and MS SQL. *Worked with Object Oriented Design principles like Encapsulation, Abstraction, Polymorphism, Inheritance. *Strong Expertise on Presentation - Web Front End, Business Logic tiers, Middleware & Backend Database tier of the system. *Experience in using IDE tools such as Eclipse, NetBeans, Visual Code, and STS. *Experience in using various Configuration Management tools like Tortoise SVN, CVS. *Experienced in developing web-applications using various Design Patterns including session facade, MVC, Data Access Object, Singleton and Factory Pattern. *Quick to learn new technologies and ability to work in tight schedules on different applications concurrently.

Skills

- LANGUAGE
- JAVA, J2EE (SERVLETS, JSP, JDBC, JAVA BEANS, JSF).
- WEB TECHNOLOGIES
- HTML/DHTML, XHTML, CSS, XML, DOM/SAX, J2EE DESIGN PATTERN
- FRAMEWORKS
- SPRING, SPRING BOOT, HIBERNATE, JSF, Angular 2.
- IDE'S
- ECLIPSE, NET BEANS, MAVEN, STS.
- APPLICATION SERVERS
- JBOSS, APACHE TOMCAT.
- DATABASES
- MYSOL, ORACLE, MICROSOFT SERVER.
- SCRIPTING LANGUAGE
- JAVASCRIPT, AJAX, ANGULAR JS.
- TOOLS
- BUILD: ANT, MAVEN. LOGGING:LOG4J.
- VERSION CONTROL: CVS, SVN. TESTING: JUNIT, JQUERY.
- OPERATING SYSTEMS
- WINDOWS 2000, WINDOWS XP, WINDOWS VISTA, WINDOWS 7,10.

Experience

08/2017 to 11/2017

Software Engineer Trainee Booz Allen Hamilton Inc. il/4 HI

- Data Boss International Corp.
- is a IT consultant in New Jersey, which work with different clients in USA.
- Here the project is Website Development and maintenance.
- Responsibilities:.
- Understanding the business requirements and preparing the design document.
- Participated in designing, coding, testing phases of the SDLC.
- Involved in Agile software development lifecycle which involves designing, coding, testing, debugging and support.
- Developed User interface using JSP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Ajax and jQuery.
- Used Hibernate Template of Spring Framework and Hibernate Interceptors.
- Developed database access mechanism by using by Hibernate ORM framework.
- Developed SQL, PL/SQL and Stored Procedures on MySQL.
- Used various Core Java concepts such as Multi-Threading, Exception Handling, Collection APIs to implement various features and enhancements.
- Environment: Core Java, Java, J2EE, JSP, HTML, JavaScript, CSS, Ajax, JQuery, Spring Framework and Hibernate, Junit, Apache Tomcat, Agile, PL/SQL.

01/2017 to 05/2017

Java Developer Ally

- University of central Missouri is a State university.
- Here I worked under Prof.
- Sunae Shin, who taught Advanced Software Engineering and Software Engineering.
- Here I developed a project for class registration and class allocation in the Course Advanced Software Engineering.
- · Responsibilities:.
- Developed UI modifications for portal using HTML, CSS, XML and JavaScript.
- Involved in Drawing Case diagrams, Class diagrams, and Sequence diagram for each scenario.

- The application is designed using J2EE design patterns and technologies based on Spring MVC architecture.
- Developed and implemented the MVC Architectural pattern using Spring framework including JSP, Servlets, and EJB.
- Extensively used JavaScript for client-side validations and for capturing dynamic events.
- Used ANT build tool for compilation and generation of war file.
- Loading data from Text Files to Database by using SQL Loader.
- Developed the modules using Servlets, Java2EE and JDBC for connecting with MySQL.
- Writing queries in for the database managements.
- Developed stored procedures, triggers in MySQL for lowering traffic between servers & clients.
- Environment: Spring, Spring Boot, JavaScript, Tomcat server, Servlets, Java2EE, JDBC, xml, Eclipse Maven, Hibernate.

09/2014 to 12/2015

Systems Engineer The Kemtah Group i1/4 Fort Shafter

- Infosys is a leading IT company in India.
- Where I worked on a Medtronic (B2B-E- commerce) web application development.
- It's an e-commerce web site and we developed the web application for a medical company which is user friendly and online shopping.
- Responsibilities:
- Understanding and analyzing the Client Requirements with existing flow and functionalities.
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) of the application like Requirement gathering, Design, Analysis and Code development.
- Created detailed designs such as Sequence, Activity and Class Diagrams using UML.
- Extensive Programmatic experience on AJAX, JavaScript, and jQuery.
- Developing the Java bean Classes and configure them in XML files.
- Involved in writing impex file and execute them in Hybris.
- Implemented the data access layer using Hibernate persistence framework through Hybris Suit.
- Integrating the current work flow with the existing workflow and Testing all the functionalities.
- Developed the server-side components using Spring, CSS3, HTML5, and Java.
- Involved in developing DAO Layer using Hibernate and Singleton, Factory and Design Pattern.
- Written complex SQL queries and Used SQL developer for interacting with data base.
- Developed the enterprise application by integrating JSF/Spring/Hibernate Frameworks.
- Developed JavaScript/jQuery for UI component Developments and validations.
- Environment: Java- JDK 1.8, Spring MVC, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, XML, Hybris, Microsoft SQL, JDBC, Servlets, JSP, Java Multi-Threading, Java Servlet, JSP, JUnit, Eclipse.

11/2013 to 07/2014

Jr Java Developer Infosys Ltd i1/4 Remote

- we the team of 3 members named Satya Sundar Kumar Bandiguptpau doing Masters of Science in Computer Science, IK Chaitanya
 preparing for Indian Civil Services and Anupam Sharma Evani who is currently working as a Scientist in Indian Space Research
 Organization(ISRO).
- We together used to give Ideas and help the students in developing the final year projects in computer science and Embedded Projects.
- We all together developed more than 80 management projects using Java.
- Responsibilities:.
- Used to Assist the students who need help finding the Projects suits their curriculum.
- Developing and helping my teammate in developing java applications.
- Doing Documentation for projects we did.
- Explaining the students about the project and the approaches they should follow to develop the project.
- Helping the students to develop the projects and making documentations.
- Involved in various phases of development of various web projects using JAVA.
- Writing Queries to populate data using JDBC.
- Designing Various Html Pages using HTML and CSS.
- Environment: Java- JDK 1.8, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS, XML, MYQL, JDBC, Servlets, JSP, Eclipse.

Education and Training

Dec 2017

Master's Degree: Computer Science University of Central Missouri Computer Science

Computer Architecture, Oops with Design Patterns, Advanced Operating Systems, Advanced Algorithms & Data Structures, Advanced Database Systems, Compiler Design & Construction, Software Engineering, Advanced Software Engineering, Data Mining. May 2017

Bachelor of Technology: Electronics & Communication Engineering Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University India Electronics & Communication Engineering

C-Programming, IT-Workshop, Managerial Economics and Financial Analysis and Management Sciences, Operating systems. Skills

Agile, AJAX, ANT, APACHE, B2B, C-Programming, consultant, CSS, CSS3, Client, clients, CVS, VERSION CONTROL, DAO, Data Mining, DATABASES, data base, Database, debugging, Designing, Documentation, DOM, DHTML, e-commerce, E-commerce, Eclipse, Economics, EJB, XML, features, Financial Analysis and Management, Drawing, HTML, HTML5, IDE, J2EE, Java, JSP, BEANS, JAVA

BEANS, JavaScript, JBOSS, JDBC, JQUERY, LOG4J, LOGGING, Managerial, access, Microsoft SQL, WINDOWS, WINDOWS 7, WINDOWS 2000, WINDOWS XP, MVC, MYSQL, enterprise, Oops, Operating systems, Operating Systems, ORACLE, developer, PL/SQL, coding, Requirement, Research, SDLC, SERVERS, Servlet, SERVLETS, SCRIPTING, Software Development, Software Engineering, SQL, SQL Loader, Tomcat, UML, User interface, VISTA, web application development, Website Development, web site, workflow, Written, XHTML